一个普通的渔夫怎么对 这公司这么了解?
How does a simple fisherman know so much about the company?
你到底干还是不干?
You gonna do this or not?
干 不过一旦我们出去了 你就是我们的担保了
Yes,but once we're out,I consider you collateral.
林肯惹的祸比他解决的问题还多
Lincoln causes as many problems as he solves.
他必须靠自己逃脱 我觉得你可以帮他
He needs to get way,and I think you can assist him.
我只要领先一步 你就能拿到5万
I stay one step ahead,and you get 50 grand.
怎么了?
What happened?
和你说的一样 她来找我了
She came up to me just like you said
给了我一笔钱 叫我在背后说你坏话
and offered me a bunch of cash to talk behind your back.
-那么你还是按计划执行 对吗? -当然
-So we stick to the plan,right? -Yeah.
很好
Cool.
我发现了一本护照
I found a passport.
格雷・米勒是谁?
Who's gary miller?
我在想办法让我们两个在一起
I've been working on a way for us to be together.
詹姆斯 你叫我怎么相信你?
James,how-how can I believe you?
你让我如何再去相信你?
How can I believe anything anymore?
我们找到办法从这儿出去了吗?
we got a way out of this?
我们必须给地道找个支撑物
We need some kind of support brace for the tunnel.
不然呢?
Or what?
不然地道会塌陷 我们会被活埋的
Or the whole thing collapses,and we're buried alive.
不用找借口了
No more excuses.
帕帕的死都是因为这个美国佬
Papa's dead because of this yankee.
我要亲手杀了他
I'll kill him myself *****
除非他从笼子里生还了
if I hav he survived the box.
那又怎么样?
So what?
狱警盯上了斯科菲尔德
The guards went after scofield.
但赢的人是斯科菲尔德
Scofield won.
现在他是这儿的英雄了
He's a folk hero now.
听着 我和你一样都 非常想把斯科菲尔德干掉
Look,I want scofield dead as much as you,
但绝不会以起义为代价
but not at the cost of an uprising.
你的信
Mail call.
那人是谁?
Who's that?
是我儿子
That's my son.
伯格威尔说一切安全
Bagwell gave the okay.
暂时没人
The coast is clear.
我们得走了
We gotta go.
我没想到还能再见到你
I didn't think I'd see you again.
只要有人走进那笼子里 就会
Once someone goes into the box,it'S
那是一场误会
it was a misunderstanding.
他们想和你谈谈直升机的事 对吗?
They wanted to talk to you about the helicopters,right?
什么直升机?
What h were ****
你们真的打算逃出去?
you really trying to escape?
我不知道你在说什么 我想你自己也不知道吧
I don't know what you're talking about,and neither do you.
跟你说个事 伯格威尔跟我们一起走
Just so you know,bagwell's coming with us.
你当时不在
You were gone.
他有我们需要的东西 我没别的办法
He**** we needed. I didn't have a choice.
好的
Fine.
那么新的计划是什么?
So what's the new plan?
-你告诉他了吗? -是的
-Did you tell him? -Yeah.
我要跟着你走
I am coming with you.
我无所谓
Okay by me.
大家都听到了吗? 你听到了吗? 警官
Everyone heau hear that,lawman?
但是你得待在这里
But you're staying up here.
我想我刚才说的还不够清楚
Maybe I didn't enunciate myself.
楼下的工作需要两只手
The work downstairs requires two hands.
嘿
Hey.
我们需要有人待在外面 以防萨米回来
We need somebody to stay outside in case sammy returns.
我还以为我们没法凿穿这玩意儿
I thought we couldn't dig through this stuff.
找跟柱子撑住是关键
The bracing's gonna be tricky.
除非地道有适当的物体进行支撑 不然会全部坍塌下来
Unless the tunnel gets the proper support,it's all going to come down on our heads.
我们该找些做支撑的材料
We should have the materials for the braces,
但是我们得找把锯子 把它们锯成合适的大小
but we'll need a a saw to cut them to size.
还要把锤子
And a hammer.
你能帮我们解决这问题吗?
Can you help us out?
好的 交给我吧
Yeah. I can do that.
只有2天
Two days.
如果不行呢?
And if not?
只有2天
two days
古勒莫应该备好了我们需要的一切
Guillermo should have everything we need.
你知道他在哪儿 对吗?
You know where he is,right?
我觉得 呃
I think it's,uh
在这条走廊的左边
it's down this corridor on the left.
走到走廊中间部分
Halfway down.
40号牢房
Cell 40.
沿走廊走 靠左手边 40号牢房
Down the corridor on the left. Cell 40.
没问题
Okeydoke.
你是不是已经迷路了? 西奥多
Are you lost already,teodoro?
不是
No.
不过迷路的是你
But you are.
越狱 第三季 第10集
This is my room now.
这个房间现在归我了
You're done in here.
这儿已经没你的事了
If you had gone after scofield today,all would have been forgiven.
如果今天你抓了斯科菲尔德 那还可以原谅
This is suicide.
你这是在自杀
Shut up,old man
闭嘴 老东西
I'll take my chances.
我会碰碰运气
yeah.You think you can run sona?
是啊 你觉得你管得了索纳?
You couldn't even run shipments from one dock to the other,
你连两码头间运货都办不了
but I still keep you by my side.
但我仍然把你留在我身边
I'll let you walk out of here out of respect for what you were.
看在你过去的份上 我会让你离开的
Come on
快起来
Get the hell out of here
滚出去
All of you ready to do this?
你们都准备好了?
Until lechero gets back,we should start looking for pieces about four feet in length.
勒切罗回来前 我们得开始找材料了 像这样4英尺长的
I'm running things now
现在开始我是头儿了
Anyone got a p*****.
如果谁有意见
come get it
就自己来领鸡爪
Good.
非常好
First order of business,
第一件事儿
a case of rum to the man who brings me michael scofield
谁带迈克尔・斯科菲尔德来见我 这箱朗姆酒就归他
don't worry
别担心
we'll be there with all the cash
我们会带着钱去那儿的
okay? Gracias.
行了吗? 谢谢
Osberto.
奥斯伯特
That's who you want to talk to.
他是你们要找的人
This guy on the up-and-up?
这个人信得过吗?
The guy I was running things into sona for arranged this,
我给索纳安排的事 是这个人帮忙弄的
so it's as up as it's gonna get for this kind of deal.
所以应该信得过
So,yes.
嗯 好吧
Osberto doesn't speak english,though,so how do you want to work it?
奥斯伯特不会说英语 你怎么办?
I need to meet with susan.
我去见苏珊
I'll take sofia. She can translate for me.
我带索菲亚一起去 她能给我当翻译
Don't worry about it.
这点不用担心
So when I meet with susan,what do you want me to tell her?
那么我见到苏珊的时候 你想让我告诉她什么?
Tell her whatever you think she wants to hear.
她想听什么 你就说什么
Just buy us enough time to do our thing,all right?
只要留给我们足够的时间 让我们干活就行 明白了吗?
Home stretch,papi.
最后关头了
Listen,man. I want to thank you for everything.
听着 伙计 我要感谢你 为了所有的事
Oh,linc,please.
林肯 别这么客气
When we get home,I got your back―
等我们到家了 我会照应你的
whatever you need,whatever you want.
你要什么 我都给你
That won't be necessary.
没这个必要
When I'm back home,I'm a saint.
等我回了家 我简直就是圣人了
I'm not even jaywalking.
连交通规则都不会违反
Osberto. Don't forget.
奥斯伯特 别忘了
Osberto.
奥斯伯特
Scofield steps outside that tunnel,he's a dead man.
斯科菲尔德一旦走出那个地道 他就死定了
Far as I can tell,we have two options.
就我所知 我们有两个选择
We can invite sammy on the escape
我们能找萨米一起逃跑
he can go to hell.
他可以去死
Which brings us to option number two.
这样我们就只能选第2个方案了
You wouldn't last a second in there with sammy.
你和萨米在一起 保证一秒都活不到
Would you?
那你呢?
Then I guess we'll just have to outsource.
那么我想我们只能让外人来做了
I felt sorry for the guy,
我为那家伙感到惋惜
but you don't chicken-footan ex-delta force and expect to make it out alive.
但你找一个前三角洲特种兵单挑 那是你自己活该
You're delta force?
你是三角洲特种兵?
Like chuck norris?
就像查克・诺里斯?
Norris? He wouldn't have made it through boot camp.
诺里斯? 他连新兵营都捱不过
Ex *****
打扰一下
I see you're making friends.
看来你在结交新朋友嘛
Hey,once you get the hang of it,this place ain't so rough.
一旦你适应了这里 就不会感到很难受了
Yeah.
是啊
Too bad.
太遗憾了
Too bad what?
什么太遗憾了?
You were right. We got a little plan going on.
你是对的 我们正在密谋一个计划
But,you know,if you're putting down roots
但是 如果你想要定居
no,no.
没 没
You were saying
你刚才说
We're supposed to be out of here in 48 hours.
我们将在48小时内离开这里
Not through scofield.
不能靠斯科菲尔德
You heard the town crier.
你听到萨米叫嚣了吧
College boy's life is barely worth a case of booze.
那学生仔的贱命连一箱酒都不值
Hence our current conversation.
正因如此咱们才要谈谈
I know how you got your cherry yesterday,
我知道你昨天是怎么赢的
daubing your wraps in acetone,smothering the guy until he passed out from the fumes.
往你的护腕里抹丙酮 把他熏晕
You do the same thing to sammy,and you're in.
如果你能对萨米这么干 你就加入
Chicken-foot sammy?
鸡爪萨米?
Chicken-foot sammy.
鸡爪萨米
It's all riding on you,champ.
全靠你了 冠军
Thank you.
谢谢
This shouldn't take long.
很快就好
What are you getting?
你要弄什么东西?
Supplies.
有用的东西
For?
干啥用?
I don't want to get caught flat-footed again.
我不想再毫无准备
You know what that means?
明白什么意思吗?
No.
不
Well,these people obviously have a plan.
那帮人肯定有计划
We're gonna need one,too.
咱们也得有个计划
Does that plan include screwing over james?
计划也包括干掉詹姆斯?
Is it james or gary miller?
是詹姆斯还是格雷・米勒?
Whatever his name is,there's a part of me that doesn't want to believe he works for them
不管他叫什么名字 我不愿相信他是为那些人效力的
'cause he's the man I loved,the man who went to prison for me,
因为他是我所爱的人 为我进监狱的人
the man who was going to take me to my first trip to paris.
要带我去巴黎初次旅行的人
I haven't turned my back to that man.
我不能背叛他
Do I have your word that he's gonna be all right?
你能保证他没事吗?
Yeah.
能
Now get in.
进来吧
Do I have your word?
你能保证吗?
Yeah,you got my word.
能 我说话算话
Now get in.
上车吧
ed, we'll be in contact soon. sales are through the roof
艾德 我们即将取得联系 价格涨的没边了
hope you're working on your putting gary
希望你那有所进展 格雷
You nd out?
我刚刚发现
That"sucre"means"sugar."
苏克雷是糖的意思
Yeah.
对
So every time I say your name,I'm calling you"sugar."
所以每次呼唤你的名字 我都叫你甜心
Basically.
叫吧
I like that.
我喜欢那样
Look,I don't have a lot of information.
听着 我的情报不多
Which,I guess,that's good news for you,right?
我猜 这对你来说是好消息吧?
You care to elaborate?
你要详述吗?
Lincoln isn't cooking anything up.
林肯没什么鬼点子
He's still planning on exchanging whistler for lj.
他仍打算用惠斯勒换LJ
He hasn't been talking about running any games.
他没提过什么策略
And did he become an eagle scout last night,too?
他昨晚也成了老鹰童子军了?
Lady,he got the message.
小姐 他知道事情的严重性了
He knows he doesn't have a choice,he has to play it straight.
他知道他别无选择 他只能乖乖听从你们
Look,I could have come up here and made something up just to get paid,but
听着 我完全可以胡编乱造来糊弄你 但
I'm not trying to get on your bad side either.
但是我也不想加入你那一方
You know what?
知道吗?
I believe you.
我相信你
So,I'll call you if anything comes up.
那 我有事就给你打电话
Whoa,whoa What am I,a toothless crack whore?
哇噢 哇噢 难道我是个卑鄙无耻的婊子?
Sit down.
坐下
I keep my promises.
我信守诺言
Le I work for,they don't like to deal in greenbacks; it's just too bulky.
我的上司 他们不喜欢美钞 体积大 不好带
Cashier's check payable to cash.
银行支票可换现金
Same thing.
一样的
Half now and half when you're done.
先付一半 事成付清
keep your ears open,sugar.
耳朵机灵点 甜心
alex,come on
艾力克斯 使劲
Hold it steady
举稳当点
I am I am
我不是在举嘛
I'm gonna need a little help here
帮个小忙
I got it. I said I got it.
可以了 我说可以了
That little piece of metal's gonna hold all this weight?
那一小块金属能承受全部的重量?
All right,let go,let go.
好 放开了 放开
So,how many more are we gonna need before we get to the top?
到顶之前还有多远?
20 maybe.
可能是20
That gets us to no-man's land.
那就能到禁区了
Then what?
然后咋办?
Helicopter'd be nice.
来架直升机不错
Hey,I was supposed to kill you.
我本应该杀了你
Oh,so you're not a fisherman?
哦 那你就不是渔夫喽?
They threatened to come after my family if I didn't kill you and jump on that helicopter,
他们威胁我 如果我不杀了你 进直升机 就杀害我的家人
but I didn'T.
但我没那么做
I'm so grateful.
那我该感谢你啊
So what happened to your family?
那你家出什么事了吗?
I don't know.
不知道
Maybe I'll find out if we ever get out of here.
等咱们出来了也许就知道了
Well,it's a crazy world,isn't it?
这世界真疯狂啊 是不是?
We all agree on that.
这点 我们算达成一致了
And we have a lot of work to do.
我们有很多活要干
Where the hell is lechero?
勒切罗死哪去了?
Is everything set?
一切就绪了吗?
Huh?
啊?
Is everything set?
一切就绪了吗?
Yeah,no problemo.
是 没问题
Excuse me,sir.
打扰了 先生
Do we come to you if we need the chicken foot?
如果我们需要鸡爪 是不是来找你?
tiger pants.
老虎裤衩
Who you got a beef with?
你跟谁有过节啊?
I don't know his name.
我不知道他叫啥名字
Some caribbean guy.
一个加勒比人
Stole my wallet a while back.
前一阵子偷了我的钱包
Better think long and hard before you say another word,eh?
你说下个词之前最好考虑考虑
He's got this fruity little mustache and this ugly-ass vest.
他胡子上有酒味 穿着难看的背心
please,I'm beggin' ya.
好了 我求你了
in the ring.
格斗场见
15 minutes.
15分钟后
I never thought I'd say this,but I envy you,brad.
从没想到我会说这些 但我羡慕你 布拉德
I've wanted to shank that little calypso kid ever since I first met him.
头一次见那个小瘪三的时候就想揍他
I'm not a violent guy by nature,
我生来不是个暴力的人
but if a man makes me walk around in my grunts for two days
但如果有人烦我超过两天
yeah,that's greatatjust don't take too long to finish him off, ok
很好 速战速决
the sooner he's dead,the sooner we can get on the escape.
他死的越早 咱们越狱越早
No games. I'm in.
不准耍花样 我加入了
You're in.
你加入了
No,no,no.
没了 没了 没了
What's wrong?
怎么了?
We got to call off the fight.
必须叫停单挑
No,that's an impossibility.
不 那不可能
No,no,no,you don't understand
不 不 不 你不懂
There's got to be more acetone around here.
这里应该还有丙酮啊
No,that's it
没了 就这些
I can't go against sammy straight up
我不能赤手空拳打萨米啊
I'm a dead man
那我死定了
If you don't kill him,we are all dead.
如果你不打死他 咱们都会死
this isn't the best neighborhood.
看起来不妙啊
I've been in a lot worse.
我经历过的比这糟多了
Just stick close.
走近点
Osberto?
奥斯伯特?
Si.
是
You want to do this?
你要这样吗?
Tiene el dinero?
钱
Yeah,yeah,I got it.
是 我有
Donde esta?
在哪里?
"Where is the money?"
"钱在哪?"
*****
我要看货
I want to see the product.
"先给钱"
"Money first."
给我看货
Show me the stuff.
钱
El dinero
林肯 求你了 咱们走吧
Lincoln,please,let's get out of here.
叫他别浪费我时间
Tell him to stop wasting my time.
不
No.
告诉他
Tell him.
哦 天哪
oh,my god
大号?
Big?
重型?
It's grande?
是
Si.
问他怎样遥控引爆
Ask him how do i trigger it by remote.
砰
boom.
"拨1-1 发送"
"Dial one-one,send."
1-1 发送?
One-one,send?
嗯
yeah
拜拜
Adios.
祝你好运
Buena suerte.
你怎么不告诉我你要买炸弹?
Why didn't you tell me you were gonna buy a bomb?
告诉你 你就不会来了
You never would have come otherwi
我们需要锯子
we need that saw.
你看 我是个渔夫
You know,uh,I am a fisherman.
真的
I am.
只不过牵涉的比我告诉你们的还深一点
I'm just maybe a little bit more connected than I've let on.
我觉得这个可以
I think this is gonna work.
嗯
Yeah.
我租船 真的
You know,I run charters,just like I said
很多年了
I have for years.
但突然间 那个黑发美女格雷琴・威尔
Then one day,that brunette,gretchen well,
她问我想不想包给她公司干
she asked me if I wanted to be exclusive to her corporation,right?
以她给的钱看
And,uh,well,with the money she was offering,
我知道不是捕三文鱼那么简单
I had a pretty good idea she wasn't just trawling for salmon.
你们俩还有交情啊
So you two have history.
自从那第一份工作起 她就是我生命中彻头彻尾的噩梦
Yeah. And she's been an absolute nightmare in my life ever since that first job.
艾力克斯 我要门楔
Alex,I need a wedge.
门楔
Wedge.
他们要送的东西我已经送到了
Look,I took 'em where they wanted me to take 'em.
我得搞明白这些坐标 带回去
I have to figure out these coordinates and I have to take them back there.
别再自寻其辱了
Quit embarrassing yourself.
什么?
What?
我们不是酒吧里的妞 任你钓
We're not two chicks at a bar you're trying to pick up.
-除非你想听? -不
-Unless you need to hear this? -No.
好的 行
All right,good.
你为他们工作
You work for the company.
你逃出去之后
And when you break out of here,
你还得听命于他们 没别的了
you're gonna do whatever the company asks you to do,period.
他们在利用我 就像在利用你们一样
Well,they're using me just like they're using you.
很好 很高兴你告诉我了
Good,I'm glad you shared that with me.
我们还是开工吧
So why don't we go back to work?
行么?
How's that sound?
让那些白痴自己窝里斗去吧
Let those idiots chickenfoot themselves all they want,huh?
但是如果有人想找我们麻烦
But if one of them tries to use it on us
你不用非跟他动手
you don't have to fight that guy.
这是我的告别演出
It's my farewell tour.
剩下的那些都不行
the rest of those pieces are no good.
我们需要那些工具 迈克尔
We're going to need those tools,michael.
我猜我们只能干等了
I guess we'll just have to wait.
那本书 就是一堆坐标 对吧?
That book of yours it's just a bunch of coordinates in there,right?
也有别的东西
Among other things.
那你不会介意
So you wouldn't mind.
就是一堆数字 日期
It's just a bunch of,uh,numbers and dates.
"大门"
"Gate."
大门网业公司
Gate netting company.
我在那儿租渔网
That's where I rent my trammels.
"惊逃"
"Stampede."
我朋友的渔船
That's my buddy's cape islander.
这跟我们有什么关系?
And this is important to us how?
因为你们看错人了
It's important because I'm being accused of being someone I'm not.
我不想行动的时候 斯科菲尔德又把我甩了
And I don't want scofield ditching me once it's time to leave
他谁也不会甩了
he's not ditching anybody.
就算甩人 他也会先甩掉我
If he could have gotten rid of anybody,he would have gotten rid of me.
如果他想逃离本市
And if he tries to leave the city he knows that
他知道在他出市之前 我们就会把他供出去
we're gonna turn him in before he gets out of the city.
我上楼去找勒切罗和器材
I'm going upstairs to find lechero and his equipment.
我跟艾力克斯一起去
I'm with alex.
给我行吗?
Do you mind?
好像上面有人
Sounds like someone's up there.
如果勒切罗被困住了 我们也逃不出去
If lechero gets stranded up there,we're not getting out of here.
你认为什么时候安全了 觉得安全了 我们必须得去 上去
So when you think it's safe,or it feels like it's safe,we got to go,we got to go up.
我们谈论挑战萨米说了几个月了
we've been talking about chickenfooting sammy for months.
没人有那个胆
No one had the courage.
有油漆稀释剂吗?
do you have any paint thinner?
油漆稀释剂?
Paint thinner?
鞋油 打火机油 胶水?
Shoe polish,lighter fluid,glue?
你在这儿啊 老大
There you are,champ.
到点了
It's time.
跺他的脸 布拉德
Stomp his face,brad
这是个天大的误会
You know,this has all been one big misunderstanding.
我不是指萨米
I wasn't talking about sammy.
是 是他
It was that's him.
我指的是他
That's the guy I was talking about.
布拉德 我可没看见"古怪的小胡子""丑得要死的背心"
Yeah,I don't see no"fruity moustache,"and where's his"ugly-ass vest,"brad?
别担心 说不定你能赢
Don't worry,you stand a real chance of winning this one.
你不能整天东躲西藏的
you cannot just hide out all day.
我还能怎么样 啊?
What else can I do,huh?
我血腥统治了他们一年
I've ruled these men for a year with blood.
你觉得他们不想取前任老大的人头?
You don't think those men want to take the head of the man who wore the crown?
可能吧 但萨米就要砍下贝里克的头了
Be that as it may,bellick is about to lose his head to sammy.
这话也许不中听 但要是那样的话
You may not want to hear this,but once that happens,
我们都很清楚自己的下场
we are both very much hell you are.
斯科菲尔德会爬出洞来 直接撞上萨米
He's going to come crawling out of his hole and right into sammy's arms,
我们就再也逃不出去了
and then he and our escape are gone forever.
等等
wait.
拿了工具 立马回去
We get the tools and we come straight back.
快点
Come on
你们想看吗?
You guys want to watch the fight?
等下
You know,chill out.
我给你拿瓶酒
I'll get you a beer.
高兴了吧?
You like that?
住手
Stop it.
是斯科菲尔德
Scofield
斯科菲尔德在里面
Scofield's in there.
锁住了
It's locked.
开门
Open the door.
我没密码
I don't have the combination.
我说了 开门
I said open it now.
我开不了
We can'T. We can'T.
开门
Open it now.
我没密码
I don't have the combination.
你的人在我手里
Hey,I've got your man out here.
不开门的话 他就倒霉了
If you don't open the door,he's the one who's going to pay the price.
我还用得着他
I need him alive
你见到他们了
You saw those guys.
你觉得他们会怎么处理我们?
What do you think they've got planned?
你们在考验我的耐心
All of you is trying my patience.
你的建议呢 艾力克斯?
What do you suggest,alex?
我们得准备好
Let's be ready for them.
时间到了
Time's up.
还想再来吗?
You want another one?
那你最好说服他们
Then you better be persuasive.
迈克尔
Michael.
别开门 他有
Don't open the door He's got a gu
你会告诉我这是干吗用的吗?
Are you going to tell me what it's for?
不
No.
因为怕我告诉詹姆斯?
Because you think I might tell james?
因为你没必要知道
Because you don't need to know.
不会有事的
It's going to be all right.
-顺利吗? -不错
-How'd it go? -Good.
照你说的 我说了些她想听的话
I to her what she wanted to hear,just like you told me.
就这么简单?
That it?
对
Yeah.
行
Cool.
你给她打电话 说有情况
Listen,I want you to call her up,tell her you've got some information.
确保她来接你 上她车 好吗?
Make sure she picks you up,and get in the car,all right?
好
Okay.
都还好吗?
Is everything okay?
嗯 为什么这么问?
Yeah. Why?
她有点不安
She looks upset.
我晚点再给你电话
I'll call you later.
弄了点工具 迈克尔
Got something down here we can use,michael.
如果他们进来
If they come through that door
直接往这里戳
you hit 'em right here.
拿着
Go ahead,take it. Go ahead.
会穿透心脏
It'll puncture the heart.
你把斯科菲尔德藏在你屋里?
you were hiding scofield in your room?
看看 权力已经让你疯了
Look at you the power make you mad already.
来吧 诺曼 上
Come along,norman.******
什么急事?
What is so urgent?
林肯买了把枪
Lincoln bought a gun.
我 我问他想干嘛 他不说
I I asked him what he planned on doing with it,but he wouldn't answer.
所以我 我觉得你可能想知道
So I just I just thought you might want to know.
如果还有情况 我会再找你的 行么?
If anything changes,I'll get back to you,okay?
那天你和林肯在大厅里的小口角
You know,the other day when you and lincoln had your little spat in the lobby and you
你心烦意乱 觉得自己被抛弃了 去了街对面的酒吧
all distraught and jilted went across the street to the bar,
一个愤世嫉俗的人会觉得这是事先安排好的
a cynic might think that was staged.
我就是这样的人 甜心
I'm a cynic,sugar.
你是不是磕药了 甜心
You're high,sugar.
你们差一点就骗了我
If it's any comfort,you guys almost pulled it off.
一个波多黎各人和一个傻大个 你们真的让我信以为真了一会儿
The puerto rican and the gorilla you really had me scrambling there for a minute.
如果你不需要我帮助 那好 我不玩儿了 行不行?
Hey,if you don't want my help,fine,I'm out,okay?
在我给你的支票上有个小东西 叫做查询号
It's a little thing called a tracing number on the check I gave you.
很明显 你的金融知识掌握的还是不够啊
Apparently your extensive expertise in banking failed you that day.
你匆匆忙忙把所有25000块汇给了
You promptly wired all 25 k to
在芝加哥的玛丽克鲁兹・德尔加多
maricruz delgado in chicago at 123
勿害我大道123号
please don't hurt me lane.
-我发誓 如果她出了什么事 -如果什么?
-I swear to god,if something happens to her -if what?
什么 混蛋?
What,jackass?
你最好回去给我搞点有用的信息
You're going to go back there and you're going to get me some real information,
不然玛丽克鲁兹就要身首异处了
or maricruz and her head are going to part ways.
滚出我的车
Get out of my car.
马上
Now.
嗨 小白脸
Hey,blanco.
我抓到了你的好伙伴勒切罗
I got your good buddy lechero here.
你干嘛不去敲敲门 好让他知道你来了?
Why don't you give it the secret knock so he know's you,huh?
密码
The combination.
你怎么会以为我有密码?
What makes you think I have the combination?
照他说的做
Just do what he says.
你还要显摆这东西多少次阿?
How many times you gonna pull that little thing out?
当我觉得必要的时候
As many times as I feel necessary.
你觉得它能让你更强大吗?
What,you think it make you look strong?
它只能放大你的怯懦
All it does is magnify your weakness.
真有趣 我现在倒觉得更安全了
funny,I'm feeling pretty secure right about now.
快说 密码 老不死的
Now,the combination,old man.
我们不会再问一遍
We're not asking again.
萨米
Sammy
我要开门了
I'm opening the door.
迈克尔 不要
Michael,do not open the
放下武器
drop 'em
我说 放下武器
Drop them,I said
走
Now move
你要和他一起越狱?
You're escaping with him?
我打算告诉你这一切的 布瑞达
I was gonna tell you all about this,bredda.
只是从来没有说出来 是吗?
It just never came up,eh?
拿去吧 这是你的了
Take it. It's yours.
这个隧道 越狱的计划 所有的东西
The tunnel,the escape plan,everything.
我们可以一起走
We can go together.
我要拿走你的所有东西
I'm taking everything you got.
但是你哪儿也去不了
But you ain't going nowhere.
你们是怎么挖出这个洞的
How you finishing up this hole?
答应我 你会带惠斯勒走
Promise me you'll take whistler with you.
你在和我讨价还价?
You making demands on me? Huh?
我了解
I understand
为什么你要杀我 但是他什么都没做
why you're going to kill me,but he's done nothing wrong.
带他一起走 我会告诉你一切需要知道的事
I'll tell you everything you need to know,just take him with you.
你会需要他的
You need him.
是他一个人策划了这一切
He's the only one who figured this one out.
别担心 我会照顾好你朋友的
Don't you worry,I'll take care of your friend.
好吧
All right.
首先 你们要继续搭一些 能支撑住隧道的支架
First,you need to keep building braces to support the tunnel as you go.
你怎么做的?
How you do that?
惠斯勒会做给你看的
Whistler can show you how.
看上去你只是用了这些箱子上的木框
Look like you just make some wood squares from these boxes here.
就象我说的 惠斯勒会做给你看的
Like I said,whistler can show you.
到地表还有多远?
How much further to the surface?
不远了
Not far.
看上去不到十英尺了
Can't be more than ten feet.
不错啊 小白脸
Impressive,blanco.
很可惜你不能享受这个了
too bad you won't be around to enjoy it.
我们会被耽误多久?
how long is this going to set us back?
如果有警卫在无人区看到这个塌陷的大洞 我们就真的有麻烦了
What's gonna set us back is if the tower guards are looking at a giant sinkhole out in no man's land.
迈克尔?
Michael?
-一切都好 -对
-We're good. -Yeah.
一切都好
We're good.
一切恢复原状了
Back in business.
我要加入
I'm in.
为什么 就因为你被狠狠的揍了吗?
For what,getting your ass kicked?
不让我加入 我就到屋顶上把一切都抖出来
I'm in or I shout it from the rooftops.
算你一个 勇士
You're in,champ.
好的 你待在这儿
Okay,you need to stay here.
我去买点东西 好吗?
I got to get something,all right?
不要乱走
Don't move.
从这里你能回家吗?
can you get home from here?
可以 就两个街区远
Yeah,I'm two blocks away.
如果他不带你去巴黎 我会的
If he doesn't take you,I will.
给你 擦擦这个
Here. Use this.
-谢谢 -擦那里
-Thanks. -Right there.
你知道吗 你总是让我证明我是个渔夫
You know,for all the times you wanted me to prove I was a fisherman,
我也应该问问你是不是真的工程师
I should have been asking if you were a real engineer.
我们中的一个也许也会被埋在下面
That could've been one of us buried down there.
下次我会做的好一点的
I'll do better next time.
我下去把那些支架修复一下
I'm gonna go back down and try to salvage some of those braces.
好 我和你一起去
Yeah,I'll go with you.
下次不会这么容易了
Never gets any easier.
斯科菲尔德 有访客
Scofield,visita.
三年来我在索纳干所用工作的报酬
All the side jobs I do at sona for three years.
我都存了起来
I save all of my money.
这里有173块
It's $173.
如果你真的要越狱 这些就都是你的
If you're really leaving,it's yours.
只要你带我一起走 好吗?
Take me with you. Please?
我不想再待在这里了
I don't want to be here anymore.
你不会想参与这个的
You don't want any part of this.
你有新计划了 还是我们得从头再来
you got a plan or are we back to square one?
我有计划
I have a plan.
很好 我在外面也有动作
Good,'cause I got something cooking on the outside.
我不会再让事情失控了
I ain't walking into a buzzsaw again.
你和里面那些家伙相处的怎么样了?
How you dealing with the animals in here?
事实上 感觉越来越像一个家了
Actually,it's starting to feel like home.
惠斯勒还想让你们相信他是渔夫吗?
Whistler still pretending he's a fisherman and all this?
什么意思?
Why?
索菲亚在他另一个公寓找到了一本护照
Sofia found a passport in one of the apartments he kept.
上面的名字是格雷・米勒
Name's gary miller.
真意外啊
I'm shocked.
他是一个骗子 迈克尔
Guy's a fraud,michael.
就我所知 斯科达尔那里连鱼都没有
As far as I know,there ain't fish in scottsdale.
那么 如果他不是渔夫
Well,if he's not a fisherman
他又是什么呢?
what is he?